[song counts down: 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1]
[乐曲向下计数：7,6，5,4，3，2，1]
Hi, my name is Lynn.
嗨，我的名字叫林恩。
I'm a software engineer here at Spotify and I'll be the first to admit that I often take for granted the reliability of the internet.
我是Spotify里的一个的软件工程师，我会是第一个承认网络的可靠性是理所当然的人。
The sheer amount of information zooming around the internet is astonishing.
网络上暴涨的庞大的信息量是惊人的。
But how is it possible for every piece of data to be delivered to you reliably?
但是，如何将每一份数据可靠地交付给你呢？
Say you want to play a song from Spotify.
比如说你想从Spotify里播放一首歌。
It seems like your computer connects directly to Spotify servers and Spotify sends you a song on a
看起来像是您的计算机直接连接到Spotify的服务器，Spotify用专线
direct, dedicated line. But actually, that's not how the internet works.
把一首歌送给你。但实际上， 互联网并不是这样工作的。
If the internet were made of direct, dedicated connections, it would be impossible to keep things
如果互联网是由直接的、专用的连线组成的， 那它就不可能在数百万用户连线时
working as millions of users join. Especially since there is no guarantee that every wire and computer is working all the time.
保持工作状态。尤其是因为不能保证所有的 电线和电脑都在时时刻刻正常运作。
Instead, data travels on the internet in a much less direct fashion.
事实上，互联网上数据是以 更不直接的方式传播的。
Many many years ago, in the early 1970s my partner Bob Kahn and I began working on the design of what we now call the internet.
很多年前，在70年代初，我和我的搭档Bob Kahn 开始设计我们现在称之为互联网的东西。
Bob and I had the responsibility and the opportunity to design the internet's protocols and its architecture.
鲍勃和我有责任和机会去制定 互联网的协议及其体系架构。
So we persisted
因此，我们坚持
in participating in the internet's growth and evolution for all of this time up to and including the present.
到现在，参与互联网 的发展和演变。
The way information gets transferred from one computer to another is pretty interesting.
信息是用非常有趣的方法从一台 计算机转移到另一台计算机。
It need not follow a fixed path, in fact, your path may change
它不必遵循固定的路径。其实，你的 路径可能会在计算机到计算机
in the midst of a computer to computer conversation. Information on the internet goes from one
中的对话发生改变。互联网上的信息
computer to another in what we call a packet of information and a packet travels from one
以数据包（packets）的形式从一台电脑 传到另一台电脑，而数据包在互联网上
place to another on the internet a lot like how you might get from one place to another in a car.
从一个地方到另一个地方流动，就像 汽车从甲地到乙地一样。
Depending on traffic congestion or road conditions, you might choose or be
根据交通拥堵或道路状况，您可能 会在每次旅行时选择一种路线或是
forced to take a different route to get to the same place each time you travel.
被迫采取另一种路线到达目的地。
And just as you can transport all sorts of stuff inside a car, many kinds of digital information can
而且，正如你可以用车运送各种东西， 多种数字信息可以
be sent with IP packets but there are some limits.
用IP数据包发送，但也有一些限制。
What if, for example, you need to move a space shuttle from where it was built to where it will be launched.
例如，如果你要运送一架航天飞机， 从建造地送到发射地，那该怎么办。
The shuttle won't fit in one truck so it needs to be broken down into pieces, transported using a fleet
一辆卡车装不下一台航天飞机， 所以它需要被拆解，用卡车
of trucks. They could all take different routes and might get to the destination at different times.
运送。卡车可以走不同的路线并且 可能在不同的时间到达目的地。
But once all the pieces are there, you can reassemble the pieces into the complete shuttle and it will be ready for launch.
當所有的组件到了，就可以重新组装 構成完整的飞机，并且随时准备发射。
On the internet, the details work similarly.
在互联网上，数据包发送运作细节也像这样。
If you have a very large image that you want to send to a friend or upload to a website,
如果您有一个非常大的图像， 想要发送给朋友或上传到网站上，
that image might be made up of 10s of millions of bits of 1s and 0s, too many to send along in one packet.
该图像可能是由数百万个1和0的位组成， 这对于一个数据包来发送的量来说太大了。
Since it's data on a computer, the computer sending the image can quickly
由于它是计算机上的数据， 发送图像的计算机可以很快
break it into hundreds or even thousands of smaller parts called packets.
将其分解成数百个甚至数千个 更小的称为数据包的组件。
Unlike cars or trucks, these packets don't have drivers and they don't choose their route. Each packet
不同于汽车或卡车，这些数据包没有司机， 他们不选择他们的路线。每个数据包
has the internet address of where it came from and where it's going. Special computers on the internet called routers
有它来自哪里和它正在去哪里的互联网地址。 因特网上的专用计算机称为路由器，
act like traffic managers to keep the packets moving through the networks smoothly.
就像流量管理器一样，使数据包顺利地通过网络。
If one route is congested, individual packets may travel different routes through the internet
如果一条线路拥挤，个別的数据包可以 通过不同的路线在互联网传播，
and they may arrive at the destination at slightly different times or even out of order.
数据包們可能在稍微不同的时间， 甚至不按顺序到达目的地。
Let's talk about how this works. As part of the internet protocol,
让我们来谈谈这是如何运作的。 作为互联网协议（internet protocol） 的一部分，
every router keeps track of multiple paths for sending packets, and it chooses the cheapest
每个路由器跟踪记录数据包的 多条发送路径，并根据数据包的
available path for each piece of data based on destination IP address for the packet.
目的IP地址为每一块数据选择 最便宜的可用路径。
Cheapest in this case doesn't mean cost, but time and non-technical factors such as politics and relationships between companies.
在这种情况下最便宜的并不意味着成本， 而是时间和非技术因素， 如政治或企間之间的关系。
Often the best route for data to travel isn't necessarily the most direct.
通常，最好的数据流动路线 并不一定是最直接的。
Having options for paths makes the network fault tolerant. Which means
有路径多选项，使网络得以 容错（fault tolerant）。这意味着
the network can keep sending packets even if something goes horribly, horribly wrong.
即使网络出现了可怕的错误， 也能继续发送数据包。
This is the basis for a key principle of the internet: reliability.
这是互联网的一个关键原则的基础： 可靠性（reliability）。
Now, what if you want to request some data and not everything is delivered? Say you want to listen to a song.
假设，请求数据时，不是所有数据包 都送达该怎么办？ 比如你要听一首歌
How can you be 100% sure all the data will be delivered so the song plays perfectly?
你怎么能百分百确保所有的数据都 将送达，以使歌曲完美播放？
Introducing your new best friend, TCP (transmission control protocol).
来见见你最好的朋友， TCP（传输控制协议）。
TCP manages the sending and receiving of all your data as packets. Think of it like a guaranteed mail service.
TCP以数据包的方式管理数据的发送和 接收。想象他是一个有保证的邮递服务。
When you request a song on your device, Spotify sends a song broken up into many packets.
当您在设备上点一首歌，Spotify 会把发送的歌曲分成许多数据包。
When your packets arrive, TCP does a full inventory and sends back acknowledgements of each packet received.
当你的数据包到达时，TCP确认接收（ack）， 并返回每个数据包的收到的确认信息。
If all packets are there, TCP signs for your delivery and you're done.
如果所有的数据包都存在， TCP标志着你已完成了你的发送。
If TCP finds some packets are missing, it won't sign, otherwise your
如果TCP发现一些数据包丢失， 他不会标记送达，否则您的
song won't sound as good or portions of the song could be missing. For each missing or
歌不会发出一样好的声音，或者可能 会丢失部分信息。对于每一个丢失或
incomplete packet, Spotify will resend them. Once TCP verifies the delivery of many packets
不完整的数据包，Spotify的将重新 发送。一旦TCP验证了一首歌请求的
for that one song request, your song will start to play.
多个包的发送无误， 你点的歌曲将开始播放。
What's great about the TCP and router systems is they're scalable. They can work with 8 or 8 billion devices.
TCP和路由器系统的优点是 它们是可扩展（scalable）的。 他们可以使用8或80亿个设备。
In fact, because of these principles of fault tolerance and redundancy, the more routers we add, the
事实上，由于这些容错和冗余原则， 我们添加的路由器越多，
more reliable the internet becomes. What's also great is we can grow and scale the internet
互联网就变得越可靠。更重要的是， 我们可以在不中断服务的情况下
without interrupting service for anybody using it.
增加和扩展互联网，让每个人都能使用它。
The internet is made of hundreds of thousands of networks
互联网是由成百上千的网络
and billions of computers and devices connected physically. These different
和数十亿台连接在一起的计算机 和设备组成。这些不同
systems that make up the internet connect to each other, communicate with each other,
系统组成网络相互连接， 相互沟通，
and work together because of agreed upon standards for how data is sent around on the internet.
携手合作，这靠的是说好的数据发送标准， 数据发送得以有所依。
Computing devices, or routers along the internet, help all the packets make their way to the
数据发送路上的计算设备或路由器 帮助所有的数据包能井然有序地到达
destination where they're reassembled, if necessary, in order.
目的地并重新组合，
This happens billions of times a day, whether you and others are sending an email, visiting a web page, doing
这种情况一天发生数十亿次，不管你是 和其他人发送电子邮件，访问网页，进行
a video chat, using a mobile app, or when sensors or devices on the internet talk to each other.
视频聊天，使用手机应用程序，还是